Should we buy insurance from a dealer
or on our own?  So see, when I went to collect my B6, the
quotation given to me for
my car was ₹1400.
I told him that brother, this is very expensive.
I will take insurance myself.  So
he said, Sir, you
get insurance from anywhere and we will get the match done.  So the
quote I got was for ₹47,000
and the name of the insurance provider was
Ekko and everything was covered in it.
Be it your fire incidents,
water damage, red bites, battery
damage, everything was covered from A to Z and
after seeing that even Mahindra was
surprised.  He said, friend, we will
not be able to match this much.  At the very least, we will pay Rs
80,000 but it cannot be less than that.
Even ₹80,000 was too expensive for me, so
I took the risk and opted for Ekko insurance.
Now
I had taken the insurance of Ekko
but I was already scared inside
because I did not have much trust in this company
because it is a completely new company.
They do not even have any physical offices.  So if there is
any problem in the claim then maybe
Mahindra will also raise its hands and say brother
why did you not take it from us?  But when this
accident happened with me, just four days ago,
a biker hit my parked car
from behind, in which you can see the
entire side panel was damaged and the
front mirror too. Now after seeing this, I got
scared that brother, now I will have to make rounds,
but as soon as I talked to their customer
support, you can see that
in their app you get the option of claim here.
In claim, you have to select your vehicle
and after that you can raise your claim.
So before raising the claim I
spoke directly to the customer support of the insurance.  He told me the complete
steps on how you can raise the claim.
Now the biggest problem I faced in this app was
when I started raising the claim, then
my
authorized Mahindra garage, this
Mahindra showroom which is here
in Dehradun, is a brand new one.  So
this was not in their app.  Their app had
more local garages and one
Mahindra showroom was DPM which is a very
old showroom.  I did
not want to get my car repaired there because I had
already had some bad experiences with
that service centre.  So I had to get the
car serviced at my preferred
dealer from where I had purchased the car.  So
I spoke to their customer support.
I told him that brother, this one was
not shown at your place in the garage.
How do I get my car repaired?  He said there
is no issue sir.  You tell us
in which garage you want it done.  Tell me his address.
Tell me the number.  I gave him all the details
that the showroom is here.  This is the
number of these service centers.  They updated the details and
started my claim.
He asked, brother, when will you take the car
?  Will you take it now, tomorrow, the day after
tomorrow?  I said friend, today is
Friday.  There is no work on weekends.
So you do one thing,
keep a schedule for Monday.  I bring the car on Monday
and then
I bring the car on the Monday after that.  He
said, brother, please tell me the time at which you will
take the car.  We will send the surveyor at the same time.
I said I will go at 1:00.
So he said, okay,
you take the car at 1:00 and the
surveyor will come there at 1:00.  I have
reached Mahindra showroom.  As soon as I reached there, the
surveyor also arrived after 5 minutes.  He
checks the car and after 5 minutes he
checks the car and asks me what happened?  He doesn't make
me write anything.  He just asks, takes a
photo, uploads it to the app and
leaves.  And after that I have to mention in the app
that brother,
how did the accident happen?  So as I wrote there that
this was the incident, what was the time, who was driving the car,
I mentioned all this, I
uploaded my IDs, like the license, the
RC of the car, I uploaded that and
I hit submit and after 10 minutes it was
written that your claim has been
approved and while all this was going on,
I was sitting with Mahindra and
telling them also, now they were
also writing from their side, I was filling all the details for them also,
then they asked whether your
survey is done, I said sir it has just been done.
And what happened after that?  He said that once the
survey is done then there is no need to worry, your
car will start getting repaired right away
and that is what happened.  I have left for home.  It is written
that the repair of your vehicle has
started.  And at first I
felt a bit gimmicky that it cannot happen so quickly
because I already have other
insurances.  The
survey did not come for two days after I went there with my car.  Now I don't
want to take the name of the insurance company.
But among all such big companies, there were
two-three because I had
many cars before and many
accidents have happened in my car before, so this used to happen in them, so
I thought
maybe this is a bit of a gimmick, but nothing like this happened,
after three days I get a call that
sir your car is ready, but
because you did
not get the insurance done in our preferred garage, it will
not be cashless, it will be your
reimbursement, I said
what is the difference in this, there is nothing in the carriage,
you will have to pay the money first and we will
refund you the money.  By
deducting the amount of your file charges at the same time.  I
thought, okay, at least the matter has been settled.   It has
also come in returns.  But you won't believe it.
When I was going to the service centre,
before going, Mahindra people
shared the invoice with me saying that brother, the
cost of the car is Rs 12,000.  So while I was
reaching my service centre,
I got a message that Bhaiya
your account has been credited with ₹14556.
Acko reimbursed me this entire amount
and deducted ₹2000 as file charges
which every insurance company has.  And
I was surprised.  I said friend, in a way this has become
cashless because normally it happens
that I have to pay the money first and
then I get the money.  But in this case,
I received the money first and later made the
payment.
You can see these screenshots with time in
which you can see and
I was surprised to see this service.  I said, friend,
I did not expect such fast service
and I also discussed this with Mahindra.
I asked, are there other people here
who bring Ekko?  So
he himself said that Sir, many people have
taken one.  Many people come and the
best service is from Ekko.  And the
second one he told was Go Digit.  Now
I had Go Digit before.  I had it when I had it, I still have it now.
So the first insurance was from
Go Digit.  But I never claimed it.
So I
cannot tell you my experience with this.  But I have taken this on myself.
So I know what the experience is like.
Now if you people are also
thinking of buying a car and thinking of taking insurance then I must say
that one is best for you.
Because if the dealer is
selling you the insurance of a car for Rs 500, then
this Aqua will give it to you at half the rate
and everything of yours will be covered in it.  And the
best part is that everything is in your hands.
You do
n't have to run after the dealer and ask, Sir,
what is my status?  What did the insurance say?
What did the surveyor say?  Because you are in
direct contact with the company.   The
company has created such a platform
that you can see in it at
which stage your car is.  What stage is your claim at?  Has
your survey been done or not?  It
shows you how much damage has been done, that is, how much of your car has been repaired, and it is very easy for you
because you get to know
exactly when your car will be repaired,
how much amount you will have to pay and
how much amount has been approved.  This makes everything
look handy to you.  There are many
big insurance companies in India
which take this thing lightly.  He is
not customer friendly at all
because we take the vehicles.  The
surveyor does not come for two-three days and even
after that when the surveyor comes, he says
that brother, your damage will be covered from the front,
not from the back.  Because they
look for reasons to reject
or reduce any claim.  But when it comes to Aago, he
asked me just once, said yes sir and
directly approved my claim.  So if
you are also buying a new car or
renewing insurance then I recommend go for
Ekko.  I have put its link below.   If
you want, you can also find out the exact quotation of your vehicle there
and you can also get insurance.  You wo
n't believe it.  My health
insurance was also from Star Health
which was about to expire.  I got it
renewed yesterday from Ekko only.
Because if any provider is providing such a good service
now, then this is the time to
disappear him.  We believe that
small companies that do
not have offices and have small platforms
may not be reliable.  There may be big companies
but even big companies are not so reliable.
And as far as Mahindra is concerned,
why didn't Mahindra also do something about this once?
Mahindra did not even ask once,
brother, why have you taken insurance from outside
?  We will not help you in this.
Because Mahindra was also involved in this thing.
Without even asking me, he first
shared the invoice with me so that
I could get the money quickly and he himself
told me that there are many people here who
bring insurance for one person.  They say
we can't sell it but yes the
insurance is very good.  So
Mahindra's support has also been very good in this.
You may not be able to digest this but it is a
fact and this is the reason why I
prefer Mahindra cars.
If you haven't seen the last video,
I had given a hint in that too.  This is what I had
said about which insurance should be taken.
I had said it indirectly and I had
also said indirectly that I have
used many vehicles.  But
I am stuck in Mahindra.
You have seen his live experience.   Little did
I know that after making that video,
I would have a minor accident the very next day.
In which
I will get a chance to share this experience
which I just had with you.
So more such videos will keep coming.  Right now
I am uploading some old videos in my channel.
So that's
not a link up right now.  Whatever videos come of this,
I will share them separately on Instagram.
So if you are not following Instagram
then you can follow that page there also.
Rest of my old videos are being
uploaded.  There will be new ones too and
after some time, we might go on a trip to India with this car as
soon as possible and
since the review of B6 is pending, that
too will be uploaded soon.  That was a car accident.  That's why
I couldn't make it, but now that the
car has arrived, it will also be made in a few days.
So see you in the new video.